All right, we're gonna pick up right where we left off.
Sorry about the technical difficulties.
All right, so we have a five bed, five bath, 6,400,
less than an acre lot built in 2024,
sold for 809 a square foot.
Let's go down and figure out the details on it.
So it sold for 1,175,
a little more than the other one that was an acre.
So that tells us that people are willing to pay our premium
even for less biggest stuff.
But one of the things I want to go over real quick is this was listed for sale and went
pending within eight days.
It could have meant it was priced perfectly or it meant the agent didn't really know what
they were doing and listed it for lower than it should have.
But let's say they knew what they were doing.
Sold for $1175.
So if we multiply that by .07, that means that seller paid $82,000 in closing costs.
So $1,175 minus $82,000 in closing costs.
Million 93,000 is around probably what they netted.
So what we can do with these sellers,
and this is just going down a little bit of a rabbit hole
real quick, I'll be quick about it,
is we can tell sellers, hey look,
stuff around your neighborhood is selling for
between one million and 1.2 million for lots.
It depends on the lot, shape, size, the exact area in the neighborhood.
If the neighbors are nice, because that's something developers care about, they want
to see if there's other new builds in the area, which there clearly is.
I'm sure you drive by them every day.
This is what I'd be saying to the seller.
You're going to probably sell for somewhere in the 1.1 to 1.1.5 range.
But the thing is, is you're going to pay $90,000 in closing costs, including commissions to
an agent and you have to deal with showings and all that BS.
So what, what I love about luxury wholesale is we're able to get stuff
under contract for damn near what they would get.
Um, if they were selling traditionally on the market, because for example,
we could lock up a property for a million 93,000.
We could go back to search.
Instead of new built, we could go to a max built of like, say, 1980.
Let's see what sold in that range in this same neighborhood.
All right, 117, teardown.
I sold this property right here, actually, on Lockspur.
1.28.
Another teardown. You can see just by looking at these properties, they're most likely teardowns.
As crazy as this sounds, all of these properties, like 3,000 square feet, 4'3", it has low ceilings,
whole thing would need to be remodeled, raised roof. People would rather just build new.
one let's see 126 million 80 1.1 another teardown you can tell by just looking at them initially
but you'll have all the information of what we really look for for teardowns but this
is giving you a great idea 1.2 million teardown 1.14 million teardown the reason a lot of
these are teardowns is just because of what they look like currently and the
current square footage. The only way it can be a luxury remodel, if it's at or
near what the square footage of new builds are going for. So we saw that new
builds are 5,500 to 7,000 square feet. So unless we can have a house that's maybe
4,500 and we could do a large remodel addition to anything except that,
anything under 4,000 square feet is going to be a teardown. The reason for
that and this just sold as well the day before Christmas Eve for 1 1 4. So what we can do
with these sellers is say, hey, you would probably sell for 1 1 4. Let's just take one
of the higher comps in the neighborhood, this one, 1 1 4, you're going to pay close to $100,000
in fees. So let's say it's at a million 40. So I can offer you more than you would net
on the market, a cash transaction, I can be very flexible with my closing timeline.
I can even offer you some time after we close if you need the money to purchase your next
house.
I don't know what your financial situation is, but that's an option.
So these are all things that I look for and I go, this is a great opportunity here.
I can get this property for a million fifty and I have a bunch of other people that bought
these new builds that we were going over earlier.
If we go back to the filters for the new builds, we'll go to more, last six months.
We'll do year built, 2023 again.
Zoom back in on this area.
So all of these people, this is new construction listed right now for 4.3 million.
Let's see how big it is.
Point eight acres.
We'll go down.
All right.
They purchased this.
I passed it.
Where's the Pius history?
All right, here we go.
They purchased it for $1.19.
So we can offer someone what they would net on the market
if you show them the right comps
and say we'll give you over what you'd net on the market.
We'll give you a $1,075.
$25,000 more than you'd probably net on the market.
But at $1,075, there's still a $50,000 assignment fee
and that's from a year ago,
but there's definitely more recent stuff
that's gone up since then.
Just normal appreciation happens in these neighborhoods,
the more new builds start happening.
But even right there,
we can offer the seller more than a lot of the comps
would suggest they would get on the market.
More flexible closing timelines.
Don't deal with realtors.
Don't deal with people walking through your house.
No negotiation process with, will you fix this?
Will you do this?
None of the normal BS that you would get
traditionally selling on the market with an agent,
we can come in and squash all of that.
Pay them near what they would get on the market.
Maybe even more in some cases and still make money.
For example, this property,
if we were to get it for a million fifty,
let's actually, let's find a teardown in this area.
Let's just do, let's reset all filters
and let's just zoom in on some properties in the area.
and live right here will figure out tear downs.
So even just looking at an aerial view of houses
can help you figure out if it's a tear down or a new build.
So when I look at the aerial view of a lot of these houses,
I go, okay, this one, small, let's see, 2,100 square feet.
No chance someone could come in and pay a million
and remodel it, given that it's 2,183 square feet.
There's no way even if you got the highest comp possible at 2183 square feet the new builds were selling for 800 square foot
You're not gonna get that but for example sake
Let's say you did your exits one seven in order to get that property to that condition
It's gonna take a heck of a lot more than 700 grand to be at the level of these new builds
So it's a tear down the great thing here and another thing I love about luxury real estate is
the way zestimates work
Traditionally, you hate.
You hate when a seller says,
oh, my Zestimate's 500,000,
I'm not gonna take an offer for 400.
This Zestimate's a million 85,000,
and we're seeing stuff sell in the neighborhood
for between one one and up to one two five for new lots.
So we can go to this person and say,
hey, your Zestimate's a million 85,
I actually think it's worth a little more than that,
and I'm willing to pay a premium
because I really need a lot in this area.
My developer has cash ready to go,
it's burning a hole in his pocket,
and we have to have a certain number of deals going on
in order to make the money we need to
to pay back our capital partners.
You can BS it however you wanna say it.
This is all stuff we'll go over throughout the course
in some different materials that you're gonna have
with talk tracks and scripts and all that jazz.
So this is a million 85.
Right off the bat, I love that about luxury
because it's 2183 square feet.
The way the Zillow algorithm works
is it takes the average price for square foot
in the neighborhood and multiplies it
by the current square footage of the house.
Why that's great for us is because these smaller homes,
the Zestimate is so low on them when it should be higher.
Zestimate doesn't take into account the lot size
and say, okay, what are other lots selling for it?
Could this be a teardown?
It doesn't know any of that.
It's just a computer generated algorithm
that says it's 2183 square feet,
the average price per square foot in the neighborhood.
Right there, you see it.
497 is what they're saying this is worth,
price per square foot.
So if we do 497 times 2183 square feet,
puts us right where that zestimate's at,
a little bit below it.
So that actually helps us,
because we can come to this seller and say,
hey, I'll give you a little bit more
than what your zestimate is.
I'll give you a million 95,000,
I'll give you two months after closing to stay in the house.
What we then do is we go back and we say,
okay, there's all those new builds that have sold.
There's people selling one right here for 5.3 million.
If we go back and change real quick,
more, we're gonna go down and do year built 2023.
Three, right away, we know that we have a ton of properties
that have sold for 4 million, 3.57 million,
all these new builds, and we can go in and just say,
hey, what are these people paying for this?
What are these people paying for their lots?
All right, of course this doesn't have
Price history back to then, let's click on another.
Let's see.
5.2 million.
So this is for sale right now.
Let's go figure out what they paid for the lot.
Not available either, perfect.
Sometimes Zilla doesn't have all this
and that's where we utilize PropStream
and some other websites.
Alright here we go, here's a big one that sold 9.3 million, very recent.
Let's look at the details on this.
An acre, 8900 square feet, they pretty much maxed out as much as they could build on that.
What did they pay for this lot?
They paid 1.4 million for this lot.
So this estimate that we saw for a million 84,000 that was an acre, we could move around
1.4 million, maybe 1.3 million to a developer like this.
And what we're gonna do is we're gonna call him and say,
hey, let's say his name's Jim.
Hey Jim, I saw you sold a property on East Paradise Drive.
I have another property right around the corner
that's an acre.
Is that something you'd be interested in?
He's not gonna say no because he just paid one four
and sold this for 9.3 million.
Most likely made probably around three million,
two to three million on a deal like this.
And we can go to him and say, hey, I have a property.
I can actually get it for you a little less
than you bought this one for.
I'm at 1.35 million on it.
Is that something you'd be interested in?
Yep, send me all the details.
And right away, we have a discrepancy
between a million 85 zestimate.
Even though that property is probably worth 115,
a developer might pay a premium, most likely will,
because they just sold this one for 9.3 million
that they paid 1.44.
So why would they not pay 1.4 again
for something current day
and pay the same thing they did?
And when did they sell this?
In 2024, in March of 2024, they sold this for 1.4 million.
So that tells me we can probably move acre lots
in this area for around 1.4 million.
The beautiful thing about that is
all of the zestimates are significantly lower.
That was one of the highest comps we've seen.
Let's look for some more,
some other ones that have sold 5 million right here.
Because this is what the average is.
The good thing about those real high ones
we get occasionally is those developers
clearly build at a higher level.
They're doing something right
where they can demand a premium
and they can also pay a premium
because they know they can get more
than other people on the back end.
So here we go, an acre.
5200 square feet sold for 5 million.
Let's go down, let's see what they paid for this.
So they,
let's see.
So this listing was removed and sometimes,
I don't wanna get down too many rabbit holes,
but sometimes what people will do
is if the listing gets removed
and then it gets listed for sale as a new build,
sometimes what happens is builders will come in
and partner with homeowners and say,
we'll build on your property. You go move somewhere else, we'll build on it and we'll
split profits with you on the back end if you just let us use the property to build on.
I'm guessing that's what happened here. Let's go find another one. Here we go, 4.8 million.
On an acre lot, again, sold for 4.8. What did they pay for this?
They paid 1.5 million in 2022. So we're seeing a trend here of stuff selling for between a million
and 1.5 million. There's one for 1.3 right here. So this one's for sale for 5.59 million. It's
accepting backups, meaning it's under contract. It's pending right now, built in 2025, less than
an acre. Let's go down and see what they paid. They paid a million fifty. Someone paid a
million fifty in 2022 and then I'm guessing lived in the house for two years and then
sold it for one point three five. So what that tells me is between one point one one
point two and up to one point five million is what I can sell something that's between
three quarters of an acre all the way up to an acre in this area.
So I would back up and find where all these are going for.
I would say right in this area,
everything I'm seeing on the outskirts isn't selling for as much.
There's 3.39 right here.
So I'd pull a list in this area right here and I would do three quarters of an
would do three quarters of an acre and larger and I would pull every single house built
before let's see I would click on a couple different addresses and see when most of the
houses in the neighborhood were built. Most of them were built in the same time in neighborhoods
like this so 76. Let's click on a different random one. Let's go over here see if this
This was built around the same time, 79.
Let's do it again.
This was built in 74.
So we're seeing mostly stuff built in the 70s, 73.
Let's take something a little farther north
just to see if it changes at all.
76.
All right, so what I would do
is I would estimate a little higher.
I'd say everything pre-1985 in this area,
I'm gonna pull a list for.
And the great thing about going to these people
and being able to say,
hey, I have a developer looking in the area,
we're actively doing builds in the area
and we're looking for more.
I don't have to bullshit about all the different stuff
you do traditionally wholesaling.
I don't have to ask him about the roof condition.
I don't have to ask him about,
Do you have a new AC unit?
When was that last replaced?
Tell me about the foundation of the house.
None of those questions matter
because we're talking about tear downs.
The house doesn't matter whatsoever.
We can talk to them about their house.
They might have some sentimental value to the house,
but more than likely they're gonna know
from driving around their neighborhood every day
to their house, seeing all these new builds,
that that's what we're gonna do,
that it's gonna be a tear down.
So the great thing about this is we don't have to try
nickel and dime with a seller over,
oh, $50,000, a new roof and an ACU,
and it's gonna be about $50,000.
And that could break the deal with this seller.
We don't have to deal with any of that.
We can come in and say,
we know properties are going for between
one one and one five to developers for tear downs.
So then we can go to these sellers and instantly say,
hey, we'd be in the low one millions as an offer to you.
And say they say, oh no, you're crazy.
We would want one three.
That's still a deal.
And we can show them comps on the market
that have sold for between one million and one three,
the ones we saw, we can walk them through the same math
that I showed you and say, you're
going to pay about $100,000 of fees on the market.
Would you rather save those fees?
And I'll be super flexible with timing with you.
If you're interested in selling,
I've never met someone in luxury real estate
for a deal like this that was interested in selling
that wasn't interested in working with me.
If you can talk to them the right way,
which you'll see in our scripts
and in all of the language that we speak to these people,
the answer will never be a firm no,
we want to go with an agent.
Because we can do the same thing
and get them the same number
and make the process of a hell of a lot easier
than an agent can and still make a lot of money on it.
So let's take an example property.
Let's just click on one.
All right, here we go.
Says it's worth just over a million.
It is 0.25 acres.
So you know what, actually we've got too far north.
Let's go down to the area
where these $3 million ones are selling
and then click on a random one.
All right, here we go.
862.5 acres.
So the reason it says 862, and this is a major benefit to us is because it's
1400 square feet. This person probably knows it's a tear down,
but I guarantee he's looking at this estimate saying, Oh, well, that's,
that's a, that's a number that I think I would need a net if I was going to sell.
And even if they're not, and they know a little bit more about the neighborhood,
We can still make numbers work if they already know what sold comps are going for
Here we go. Here's a new build
Right around the corner from this guy's house. I'm sure he looked back at the history. It's an acre
His is only a half acre and this one sold for
950,000
If we can lock this property up anywhere under a million we can move it all day long
For around one point, but let's just see in this exact little market right here
We'll do apply sold. Let's see
117 that's the one I sold
So 117
Let's see. What else 135 another tear down
A million twenty, another tear down.
A million thirty five, let's see if this one,
that one might not have been a tear down.
A million twenty eight, I'm guessing it's a tear down.
Let's see, you just gotta click around and see,
and you can tell right off the bat,
this would be a tear down.
One point two three.
So even from just looking at what other properties
that are similar are selling for,
those were all half acre properties
that were selling to developers
that were gonna tear them down and build new ones
and build something like this on it.
Some 5,500 square foot home.
We can offer this seller up to 1.15 million,
which is more than they would net
at a $1.3 million offer on the market.
And that's where we can come in
and be the saviors for these people
and say, look, I can pay you more
than you would net on the market.
And the reason I can do that is because I'm paying cash.
And the reason you'll net more is you don't have to pay
any of those costs associated.
And just to sweeten the deal,
I'll throw in two months for free you can stay
after the property closes.
So you can not be stressed at all about moving
and take your time getting out.
If you need the money for another property, use it.
But that's just something we like to offer our sellers
as a sign of good grace for working with us,
as a thank you.
So that is a brief overview of how I find markets.
Let's just go up to one of these,
that there's a ton more new builds selling for.
Let's do, let's do in the last six months,
you will go to year built 2023 and before and after.
Alright, let's find where there was other condensed areas.
Alright, up here, North Scottsdale.
Let's just click on this $4.6 million one.
.62 acre lot.
They built 6,000 square feet.
What did they pay for this?
No price history for that one.
Let's click on a better example.
3.25 million, let's see what this one sold for.
So this was on an acre.
Let's see what they paid for this.
This one doesn't have any history either.
And this will happen from time to time.
Let's see. Let's go in this little area where all these are selling for 2 million and they're
all new builds. Built in 2023. 0.33 acres. So super small. And one of the things you
can do when you start to see properties being sold that are smaller than a half an acre
is if you find a property that's a whole acre, don't just discredit it because everyone in
that neighborhood is only buying less than half acre properties for new builds.
You can go to a developer and say, Hey, I have a whole acre property that you can
subdivide into multiple properties and build two specs on, they'll pay a massive
premium for that. Let's go find the price history. All right.
760,000 and they exited for 2.6 million.
So what I would do is I would go into this area.
I would do a little more digging and find a couple others,
But then let's just, for example, say, look at the satellite view in this area.
So there's multiple lots in here.
There's a lot right here.
There's a ton of dirt over here and all of this is owned by people.
So we can go into these areas.
There's a lot right here.
You get the point.
We find markets that people are buying new builds in.
We then go figure out what those new builds sold for to the developer, and then we would
pull a list in this whole area for the lot size.
We can do 0.33 and up because we know that if we get anything like that, you find the
smallest lot possible that a new build sold on, and everything above it is what we're
looking for.
So we would go into these markets and say, okay, people are exiting for low to mid, let's
say mid 2 million, because there's a lot of 2.4, 2.6, 2.5, 2.85, all the way up to 3.8.
So we're going to pull all the different lots that are available in these neighborhoods.
And we're going to be like snipers.
We're not just pulling all of Scottsdale and looking for stuff.
We have to go specific.
And that's how you'll make a lot of money in this game.
So we know that different developers in here, 2.63, we just looked at that one, 2.4.
Let's look at this one for 2.85.
This one is just over half an acre, 0.61.
Please have price history.
Show more.
Let's see.
They were listed for a long time on the market.
Not a good example
Let's see
Let's find this one for 3.8. All right three quarters of an acre 0.86 and
Oftentimes stuff doesn't have price history like this for lots and land, which is when you'll utilize prop stream and some different
websites for things like that. Let's go look. So this is a whole subdivision that someone just
started building. There's still lots available that are owned by people that have just started
to be built around. So this one sold for just over 3 million, 3 million 80. The lot size is
is only 8,332 feet.
A tiny lot, but they built a small house on.
So that's where we can find, this is a perfect example.
Let's see if there's any price history.
I'm guessing they bought, there's not.
The reason there's not is because
someone probably locked up,
I'd say this is probably four acres right here, five acres.
Sold it to a developer who came in
and bought all of these homes.
And that's where you can find the really big deals.
And this will just happen from time to time.
This isn't really stuff we target because they're so few.
But if you can find someone,
let's go down this street right here.
Say this guy that lives in this house right here
owned all of this land.
There's markets and little areas in the market
where people own five acres.
That's where stuff gets very interesting
because you can get a property under contract
and sell it to a big developer
who's gonna build a ton of houses on it.
But initially we're just gonna be targeting the new builds.
So that gives you an overview.
As you can see again, when you filter stuff the right way
and you go to any city in the United States,
one more before we're off the call,
let's just do Atlanta, Georgia, another random place.
We're going to go homes built in 2023.
We're looking for luxury.
So let's go 1.5 million and up.
And we're probably going to have to remove the boundary.
Let's find where the more expensive stuff is.
All right.
Let's do a little higher because it looks like there's some pretty pricey stuff.
stuff in here. All right, so just north of Atlanta, 3.5 million for this new build. Let's
figure out. All right, it was built in 2024, a big lot. Let's see what they paid for this.
Not available, of course, and this will happen all the time when you're looking at these.
1.8 acre lot, sold for 3 million and it was built in 2025.
Let's hope this one has price history.
It doesn't.
You would go on prop stream.
You would find what these were sold for.
But the great thing is,
is we're seeing tons of luxury lots being sold
and not to get off of the acquisition
and list pulling part of this.
but we can easily go in and see that this one closed
for 5.9 million.
It was an acre lot built in 2024.
This one probably doesn't have price history either.
Nope, it does.
799,000.
So that's what that sold for in 2022 to the builder
who then listed it for 5.3 and ended up selling it
over list $600,000 over what they listed it for,
for 5.9 million.
First thing I would do to figure out what this person wants
So I'm going into a new market.
So I'm gonna go down, I'm gonna find who listed this.
Listed by Julie and Alan with Sotheby's.
Number is right there.
I was at 32nd what I would do to call this person,
dial, dial, dial, ring, ring.
Hey Julie, my name's Matthew.
I'm with Lux Blueprint.
We're actually helping developers in the area
find new lots to build on.
I saw you listed one and sold it down on King's Clothes
in Milton, Georgia.
Does that ring a bell?
Yeah.
Well, first off, I want to say congratulations
because I was a beautiful home.
It looks like you even sold it over what list was.
It must have been a great product.
Is the builder you were working with looking for anymore?
The answer is never going to be no
because they're always looking for more deals
and no agent's going to say no.
Yes, they are.
Okay, perfect.
Can you give me an idea of what they're looking for?
I saw this one was an acre.
Are they looking for smaller stuff at all?
What area?
What's their buy box like?
My goal is to find stuff off market for you,
and I'll make sure you're always taken care of.
We're always gonna say that,
say the pretty things that make them wanna work with you,
and they'll tell you exactly what they're looking for.
And then you go, okay, they just sold this one for 5.9.
Let's go find other properties
in the vicinity of this one.
and I guarantee there's a ton of them.
All right, 5.9 was right in here.
So there's all these other lots available
and look at the price point on them.
He paid, I forget what it was,
somewhere between seven and 800 grand for that new build.
So I guarantee he would be interested
in any lots we can find in this area.
Let's see how big this lot is.
One acre.
His estimate is $797.
If we can lock this thing up for low $700s, he's probably going to pay $800 for it.
He might even pay a little more because of what he sold that for.
But they will tell you their exact buy box.
And then another thing to look for is sometimes, it depends on the agent, but in the listing
description for the house, they will actually have...
see if they have the name of the builder by alpha fine homes. Bingo. I love when this
is in there because I can go in and find alpha fine homes luxury and sophisticated buyer.
I mean is this not the most perfect example ever. Alpha fine homes luxury homes for sophisticated
buyer. All right here we go. They have developments why alpha portfolio. Let's just poke around
in here. Here we go. Six lots available starting at 5 million. So these people are buying 19
acre countryside estates. They're buying a whole group of land and building a bunch of houses. So
six on 19 acres. So every house is going to be about three acres. So we can go figure out what
they're looking for up to 19 acres. We could buy some farmer's land from them. This one, 25 total
lots, around two and a half million. This is a perfect person I would call. I would go to contact.
Alpha Fine Homes is represented by Julie Allen. That's the agent that we saw. So it looks like
Julie's going to be the only one we can talk to right now. But for example, say Julie wasn't on
here, I would try to get a hold of Alpha Fine Homes. I would try to get a hold of someone in
and management there, maybe the owner,
and I'd say, hey, you know what?
I have a bunch of off-market opportunities in the area.
I see you guys are building a ton of spec homes.
Spec homes is kind of just the general name
in the industry they call new builds.
Or you can just say, I saw you have a ton
of new builds going on.
I have a lot of off-market opportunities for development.
What's your buy box?
Is that something you'd be interested in?
They'll tell you exactly what they're looking for,
and then you bypass the agent and you go directly
to the end buyer who's Alpha Fine Homes,
and they'll say, hey yeah, we want stuff,
10 to 15 acres in this area,
here's what we paid for these ones,
if you can find something like this, that's what we'd love.
Bam, built-in buyer, you don't even have to worry
about what you're locking it up at,
you already know what they're gonna pay,
so anything between what they said, hey yeah,
we'll pay four million for 25 acres in this area,
then I'm gonna go skip trace.
Everything that's 25 acres plus,
And I can go to those people and say,
yeah, you might get 4 million on the market,
but at 4 million on the market,
and why they'll see 4 million is because
Alpha Fine Homes just bought 25 acres for 4 million.
At 4 million on the market to this person who owns this,
if they're paying 6%, that's a quarter million dollars
in realtor fees, which is crazy.
That's where we come in and say,
hey, you don't wanna pay a quarter million dollars
of realtor fees.
Yes, you'd probably sell for four million on the market,
but that's 375 in your pocket at the end of the day.
I'd be willing to pay you three eight,
more than you do on the market,
and we can be super flexible
with what terms you need for closing.
Right there, if you can get that thing for 3.8 million,
more than he would make on the market by $60,000.
You have a $200,000 assignment if you're right there.
So that is a general overview of the acquisition,
how I target certain areas, you can do this with any city
in any state that's a major city in the United States.
Some of them might not have a ton of luxury new builds.
I don't know if Tulsa, Oklahoma has a ton
of luxury new builds.
I know every major city has areas where you can do this,
but that's where we're gonna give you our top 15
where we already have buyers.
But I do work in Atlanta,
and I've never heard of Alpha Fine Homes.
It's a great person I would get a hold of if I was you,
and they'll tell you exactly what they're looking for
because they wanna buy more
and they don't have the time to do what you and I do
and go sit on a computer, skip trace everything,
reach out to these sellers, negotiate,
get it under contract.
They are focused on the big money items for them,
which is building and development.
They don't care about paying us 200 grand
when they're building, what did they say?
They're building 25 homes, uncertain ones.
They're doing six here, 25 lots here,
four lots available here.
They're building a lot of homes
and they on six lots starting at five million,
they're probably making half a million
to a million each on those.
So they're making $6 million.
They don't care about paying us 150, $200,000
on the front end when they're making so much
on the back end.
And that's where we can come in
and solve this problem for them.
And they'll help us actually by telling us
exactly what they're looking for and what they'll pay.
So, there you go.